A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts tired by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today's case is animal protection! Folk tales have deep meanings!
!قضيّة اليوم عن رعاية الحيوانات! للحكايا الشعبية معانٍ عميقة
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
"The Crane That Returned a Favor Murder Case."
جريمة قتل ردّ جميل طائر الكركي
Hey, are you really sure this is the road?
أأنتِ متأكّدة أنّ هذا هو الطريق؟
Yeah! They should be in the marsh just ahead!
أجل، يُفترض أن تكون في البركة أمامنا
Ugh. Here we are in Hokkaido, so why no crabs or hot springs?!
يا إلهي، أتينا لهوكّايدو لكن لم نذهب لأكل سرطان البحر أو نزر الينابيع الساخنة
We can see cranes at the zoo any old time!
يمكنك رؤية طائر الكركي في حدائق الحيوانات !في أيّ وقت
Tanchou cranes are a protected species and only found in Hokkaido!
طيور كركي التانتشو فصيلة محميّة ولا يمكنك رؤيتها إلّا في هوكّايدو الآن
So what?!
وما في ذلك؟
Feeding Ground
أرض الإطعام
Another one is flying! How cool!
!طار واحدٌ آخر! يا للروعة
Are we done yet? We gotta find a place to stay
ألم تكتفيا؟ علينا إيجاد مكان للمبيت
or we'll be sleeping in the car tonight!
وإلّا سننام في السيّارة الليلة
Hey!
!أنتم
Who gave you permission to be here?!
من أذن لكم بالدخول هنا؟
Permission? Is this private property?
من؟ أهذا ممتلك خاص؟
That's right!
نعم
I'm so sorry!
!آسفون
We heard tanchous don't like people, so we came here to watch them...
سمعنا أنّ التانتشو لا تحبّ الناس فأتينا لمشاهدتها من هنا
I hope you're not crane thieves...
آمل أنّكم لستم لصوص كركي
Do I look like that kind of person?
أأبدو لك شخصاً كذاك؟
Yes!
!نعم
Say, why is this window made of tempered glass?
أخبرني، لمَ زجاج هذه النافذة من الصنف المقوّى؟
It's the same kind used in planes, right?
إنّه مثل المستعمل في الطائرات، أليس كذلك؟
Some people like to break windows for fun...
يوجد أشخاص يهوون كسر النوافذ للعبث
Do you like the tanchous?
أتحبّان التانتشو؟
Yes!
!نعم
What's so fun about taking care of cranes?
ما المسليّ في الاعتناء بالكركيّ؟
Old people make no sense.
لا أفهم تفكير المُسنّين
Hey, Dad! He asked if we'd stay the night!
!أبي! عرض علينا العمّ المبيت هنا الليلة
There's even an open-air bath nearby!
!يوجد حمّام مفتوح بالجوار حتّى
Ran-kun and Conan-kun did help me, and the tanchous are overjoyed.
،ساعدتني ران-كن وكونان-كن والتانتشو تشعر بالسرور
It's our way of saying thanks.
هذا تعبيرٌ عن امتناني
Does that mean... it's free?
أيعني ذلك... بالمجّان؟
Leave if you don't like it.
غادر إذا لم يعجبك الأمر
Nothing of the sort! We'd be glad to stay!
!البتّة! نشكرك كثيراً
It's the cranes' return favor!
إنّه ردّ جميل الكركي
Yeah!
نعم
That there is my home.
منزلي هناك
I live alone now.
أعيش بمفردي الآن
Your wife passed away five years ago?
تُوفيّت زوجتك قبل خمسة أعوام
I've lived all alone ever since.
عشتُ بمفردي مذ آنذاك
This thing looks alive!
يبدو هذا الشيء حيّاً
I stuff tanchous that die from injuries or illness
أقوم بحشو التانتشو التي تنفق من الإصابات أو المرض
and donate them to schools and museums.
وأتبرّع بها للمدارس والمتاحف
Hello, there!
!مرحباً، أهلاً بكم
This is my brother, Tamotsu. He started sponging off me ten days ago.
هذا أخي تاموتسو، بدأ الإقامة المجّانية هنا قبل 10 أيّام
He's a worthless painter.
إنّه رسّام غير ناجح
Didn't need the "worthless" part, Brother.
لا داعي لإضافة "غير ناجح" يا أخي
I just told the truth. You lack observational skills.
قلتُ الحقيقة فقط، تفتقر لمهارة الملاحظة
It's your fatal flaw.
إنّه عيبك القاتل
This here is Mori-san from Tokyo.
هذا موري-سان من طوكيو
I'm a detective.
أنا مُتحرٍّ
Detective?
مُتحرٍّ؟
Machida Tamotsu (53) Painter
(ماتشيدا تاموتسو (53 رسّام
Are you the famous Mori Kogoro-san?
أأنت المتحرّي الشهير موري كوغورو-سان نفسه؟
My reputation's even made it to Hokkaido, has it?!
وصلت أصداء سمعتي هوكّايدو حتّى إذاً؟
No.
لم تصل
Tamotsu is from Tokyo.
تاموتسو من أهل طوكيو
Oh, I see...
...هكذا إذاً
What is this tempered glass for, Mister?
فيما ستستعمل هذا الزجاج المقوّى يا عمّ؟
I'm going to use it in that window, so I can watch the tanchous from it.
سأركّبه مكان زجاج تلك النافذة كي أستطيع مشاهدة التانتشو منه
Dad!
!أبتاه
Why are you two here?!
ما الذي جلبكما؟
Are you really donating your estate to the village?!
!هل ستتبرّع بكلّ ثروتك للقريّة حقّاً؟
It's not true, is it, Dad?!
هذا ليس صحيحاً، أليس كذلك يا أبي؟
It's true.
إنّها الحقيقة
I want it to take care of the tanchous and other migratory birds forever!
أنوي الاعتناء عبر ذلك بالتانتشو وبقيّة الطيور المهاجرة للأبد
What?! What about taking care of me?!
!لا يُعقل! اعتني بي بدل تلك الطيور
Boutique Manager Office Worker
(ماتشيدا نوريكو (29 مديرة متجر زينة
Dad! Help me! My boutique's going to be taken over!
أبي! ساعدني! سأفقد ملكيّة !متجر الزينة خاصّتي
Quit it! We have company!
!يكفي! لدينا ضيوف
Damn! All any of you want is money!
!يا إلهي، كلّ ما تريدونه جميعاً هو المال
Come on, we're family!
!أين المشكلة؟ نحن عائلة
Hey, why isn't there a fire going?!
ما هذا؟ لا توجد نار في موقد الحطب؟
Don't, Hiroshi-kun!
!كلا يا هيروشي-كن
Eh?
!توقّف
What was that for?!
!ما الذي تفعله؟
A turtledove made its nest on the chimney last spring!
بنت حمامة قُمرية عشّها فوق المدخنة في الربيع الفائت
She's since left it, though.
مع أنّها تركته
She might come back this spring!
!قد ترجع في الربيع القادم
You're not to touch anything in this house, not just the fireplace!
اسمع، لا يحقّ لك لمس شيء !في هذا المنزل، ليس الموقد فحسب
Bird, birds, birds! Are birds more important than your own children?!
طيور طيور طيور! هل الطيور أهمّ عندك من ابنيك؟
What a great parent!
!يا للأب الرائع
Tamotsu, did you call these two here?!
تاموتسو، هل أنت من استدعاهما؟
Yeah. I knew you wouldn't like it,
،أجل، عرفتُ أنّ الأمر لن يروقك
but I felt it was best to discuss this sooner rather than later...
لكن ارتأيتُ أنّ مناقشة الأمر بصراحة أفضل الآن من لاحقاً
How egotistical.
لم يكن عليك ذلك
Your Uncle Tamotsu probably told you,
،سمعتَ من عمّك تاموتسو غالباً
but an attorney is bringing the form here at 5:00 today.
لكن سيجلب مُحامٍ الوثيقة هنا في الخامسة اليوم
The minute I stamp it, my 300 million will go to the village once I die!
لحظة ختمي عليه، ستنتقل كلّ !الثلاثمئة مليون ينّ للقرية عند وفاتي
300 million?!
!ثلاثمئة مليون؟
Then I'll talk with that attorney!
!سأقابل ذاك المُحامي
300 million for tanchous?! You're out of your mind!
!ثلاثمئة مليون للتانتشو؟! هذه سخافة
There's no point!
لا فائدة من مقابلتكِ له
I've already given you your amount of inheritance required by law!
أعطيتكما النسبة المفروضة !من الميراث بالقانون سلفاً
It wouldn't hurt to visit your mother's grave!
لن تضرّكما زيارة قبر أمّكما
Damn him! Now what do we do?!
الأب الكريه! ماذا نفعل يا أختي؟
I'll talk to the attorney! I will put an end to this!
!سنقابل المحامي! سنردعه عن هذا بلا شكّ
Geez. This is some place we wound up staying at...
...يا إلهي، أيّ بيت سنبيت فيه
You'll be all better soon! Just hang in there!
!ستُشفى قريباً، تماسك
He used to be a CEO?
كان رئيساً في السابق؟
Yeah. He had a car dealership in Tokyo.
أجل، كان يملك معرض سيّارات في طوكيو
My sister fell ill eight years ago and moved here with him to recuperate.
،أُصيبت أختي بمرضٍ قبل ثمانية أعوام وانتقلت هنا معه للتعافي منه
Just the two of them? What about their kids?
اثنانهما فحسب؟ ماذا عن ابنيهما؟
Noriko and Hiroshi didn't want to leave Tokyo,
قالت نوريكو وهيروشي أنّهما ،لم يريدا مغادرة طوكيو
so my brother gave them their inheritance early.
فأعطاهما أخي ميراثهما باكراً
And they used it all up? I'm so jealous...
...واستنفداه؟ أشعر بالغيرة
Stop! What're you--
...أنت! ما الذي
Quiet! It ain't loaded! Or are you blind?!
!اصمت! لا سهم به ألا ترى؟
Move!
ابتعد
What a horrible son.
يا للابن السيّئ
I'm alive again...
...عادت الحياة لي
But, there's something missing...
...لكن هناك شيءٌ ما مفقود
I don't like the sound of this...
...يراودني شعورٌ سيّئ
Geez! Get your own sake, will ya?!
يا إلهي، اجلب الساكي الخاص بك بنفسك
Huh?
ماذا؟
That hits the spot!
!لذيذ
What do you think, Mori-san? Isn't it a great hot spring?
ما رأيك يا موري-سان؟ أليس الينبوع الساخن رائعاً؟
The best! No complaints from me!
!إنّه الأفضل! لا تذمّر البتّة
Glad to hear it!
يسرّني سماع ذلك
Where are you headed?
أين تتّجه؟
Actually, I've been here for ten days, but my sketchbook is still blank.
في الواقع، مضت عشرة أيام مذ أتيت هنا لكن لا يزال دفتر الرسم فارغاً
Thought I'd head to the feeding ground to sketch some tanchous.
خطر لي أن أتجّه لموقع الإطعام لرسم التانتشو
Well, enjoy yourselves--
...فلتستمتعوا بوقتكم
Here you go!
هاك
Thanks!
!شكراً لك
Oh, yeah. I'll stop by again at around 5:00 when the attorney arrives,
بالمناسبة، سأعود عند الخامسة عندما يصل المحامي
so please enjoy yourselves until then!
لذا استمتعوا بوقتكم حتّى حينها
Sure! I'll enjoy myself plenty!
!أجل! سنحرص على ذلك
Dad! You should get out before he gets here!
!أبي! عليك الخروج قبل أن يصل
Not yet! There's no telling when I'll get to visit another hot spring!
ليس بعد! لا أعرف متى قد أدخل !ينبوعاً ساخناً بعد هذه المرّة
It's your own fault if you wind up fainting!
!ستكون غلطتك إذا أُغمي عليك
Hiroshi-san... Is he going back to Tokyo?
هيروشي-سان... أيرجع لطوكيو؟
So dizzy...
...أشعر بالدوار
Haven't you ever heard of limits?!
ألا تعرف الالتزام بالحدود؟
I don't feel so good...
...أشعر بتوعّك
Of course you don't.
بالطبع
You were in there for two hours and swam after drinking!
فقد بقيت في الماء لساعتين !وسبحت بعد الشرب
Is he all right?
أهو بخير؟
He's just dizzy! Anyways, did you get any drawings done?
،يشعر بدوار فحسب. بأيّ حال هل أنهيت رسم التانتشو؟
Yep. As you can see...
أجل، كما ترين
Wow! You're really good!
!مذهل! أنت بارع
Well, I should be going back. Take your time, now.
،حسناً، سأرجع الآن فلتأخذوا وقتكم
Thanks...
شكراً
Yamagami Tatsuo (58) Attorney
(ياماغامي تاتسو (58 محامي
Evening, Tamotsu-san! Is Shuzo-san home?
،مساء الخير يا تاموتسو-سان هل شوزو-سان في البيت؟
Yeah, he should be waiting for you. Come on in.
أجل، يُفترض أنّه بانتظارك. تفضّل
The window's broken!
!زجاج النافذة محطّم
Brother!
!أخي
Oh, no!
!مصيبة
No good! It's locked from the inside!
!لا جدوى! إنّها مقفلة من الداخل
What's going on?
أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
My brother's been killed with an arrow!
!قُتل أخي بسهم
You can't be serious...
...لا يُعقل
Dad!
!أبي
Don't come in!
!كلا! لا يمكنك الدخول
Uncle! Hiroshi ran off!
...هـ-هيروشي! يا عمّي، هيروشي قد
Calm down, Nori-chan!
!اهدئي يا نوري-تشان
You look for Hiroshi-kun! I'll tell Detective Mori at the hot spring!
فلتبحثي عن هيروشي-كن! سأخبر أنا المتحرّي موري في الينبوع الساخن
You call the police with the phone by the door!
لتتّصل أنت يا ياماغامي سينسي بالشرطة !من الهاتف عند المدخل
Right...
!حـ-حسناً
So, the crossbow was shot from outside...
يبدو أنّ القوس أُطلق من الخارج
The window is locked, and the door was locked from the inside?
كانت النافذة مقفلة، وكان باب الغرفة مقفلاً من الداخل، صحيح؟
Yes. He always locks it at 4:00 to watch his videos.
أجل، يقفلها عند الرابعة يومياً لمشاهدة أشرطة فيديو
He would watch videos of my late sister every day.
يشاهد أشرطة لأختي المُتوفّاة يومياً
He probably didn't want anyone to see him visiting her...
لم يرد أن يراه أحد وهو يجلس لرؤيتها غالباً
So, he had the windows made of ground glass?
لذا كان زجاج النافذة زجاجاً مصنفراً؟
He was about to put in tempered glass so he could finally
كان سيستبدله بزجاج مقوّى كي يستطيع أخيراً تجاوز حزنه
get over the sadness and watch his tanchous whenever he wanted...
ومشاهدة التانتشو متى يحلو له
But he was murdered just before he could...
وقُتِل قبل أن يستطيع
There's a mark on it...
يوجد أثر
The arrow was shot from this window?
أُطلق السهم عبر هذه النافذة؟
What's this?!
ما هذا؟
Why are the shards all lined up?!
لمَ شظايا الزجاج متراصّة؟
And there's another mark on the floor...
ويوجد أثر آخر على الأرض
Uncle Tamotsu!
!عمّي تاموتسو
Where's Hiroshi-kun?!
!أين هيروشي-كن؟
I can't find him anywhere!
!لم أجده في أيّ مكان
And our car is gone!
!واختفت السيّارة
We saw Hiroshi-san drive off just after 5:00...
رأينا هيروشي-سان يغادر بالسيّارة بعد الخامسة مباشرة
How'd he seem?!
كيف كان؟
He seemed in a real hurry...
...بدا أنّه في عجلة
Suspicious...
...مثير للشبهة
Soot?
سخام؟
There's soot gone in some places!
!السخام مُزاح في عدّة مواضع
An unburned wood chip?
قطعة خشبية غير محترقة؟
Alright, you!
!أنت
No nosing around the crime scene!
!لا تتطفّل في مسرح الجريمة
Hiroshi!
!هيروشي
Hiroshi-kun!
!هيروشي-كن
I'm Ezomatsu, of the Hokkai Police.
أنا إيزوماتسو من قسم شرطة هوكّاي
This man has confessed to killing his father with this crossbow.
اعترف هذا الابن بقتله أبيه باستعمال هذا القوس
Confessed?!
اعترف؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I'm the famous Tokyo detective, Mori Kogoro!
أنا المتحرّي الشهير في طوكيو، موري كوغورو
Famous detective? Mori what?
المتحرّي الشهير؟ موري ماذا؟
Kogoro...
...كوغورو
Guess my name really hasn't spread to Hokkaido...
يبدو أنّ اسمي لم يصل هوكّايدو بالفعل إذاً
It's strange!
...غريب
What is it?! Something's not right!
!ما الأمر؟ هناك شيء يضايقني
I just meant to scare him, not kill him!
!لم أنو قتله، بل إخافته فقط
I aimed for that stuffed tanchou...
صوّبتُ نحو ذاك التانتشو المحشوّ
I thought if I scared him, he wouldn't donate his fortune away...
ظننتُ أنّه لن يتبرّع بثروته إذا أخفته
So, you took the crossbow from the workshop?!
لذا أخذت القوس من الورشة؟
When I peeked inside,
،عندما استرقتُ النظر خارجاً
I saw him on the sofa, watching a video of Mom...
رأيتُه على الأريكة يشاهد أشرطة فيديو لأمّي
I aimed at the tanchou, took two steps back, and shot!
صوّبتُ نحو ذاك التانتشو وتراجعتُ خطوتين، وأطلقت
That scare ya?! Next time it won't be a--
...هل أفزعك ذلك؟! لن يكون الطائر المرّة القادمة
I didn't want to do it!
!لـ-لم أرغب بفعل ذلك
But my sister kept telling me to!
!لكن أختي أصرّت عليّ
What?! I never said to kill anyone!
!ما الذي تتفوّه به؟! لم أخبرك أن تقتل أحداً
And that was only because Uncle Tamotsu said
كما اقترحتُ ذلك لأنّ عمّي تاموتسو قال
Dad might change his mind if we really scared him!
أن أبي قد يغيّر رأيه إذا أخفناه حقّاً
Hold on, Nori-chan! I would never say anything like that!
!مهلك يا نوري-تشان! يستحيل أن أقول شيئاً كذلك
There must be some misunderstanding.
لا بدّ أنّك أسأتِ الفهم
A feather in his back pocket... Is it a tanchou feather?
،هناك ريشة في جيب بنطاله الخلفيّ أهي ريشة تانتشو؟
Feather?!
!ريشة؟
I thought so! But, this isn't enough to--
...كما ظننت! لكن لا يكفي هذا
Wait! The skylight!
!لحظة! النافذة العلوية
Yes! I found it!
!حسنٌ، وجدته
The peculiar tanchou sketches...
،رسمات التانتشو الغريبة
The mark on the tempered glass...
،والأثر على الزجاج المقوىّ
The lined-up glass shards and mark on the floor...
وشظايا الزجاج المتراصّة !والأثر على الأرض
And, the wood chip in the fireplace!
!كما قطعة الخشب في الموقد
One thing connected them all!
!ارتبط جميعها بخيط
Hiroshi-san isn't the killer!
!هيروشي-سان ليس القاتل
Believe me! I really didn't mean to kill him!
!صدّقني رجاءً! لم أنو قتله حقّاً
Alright, alright. We can continue this discussion back at the station.
حسناً، حسناً، سنسمع كلّ ما لديك بعدما نصل المركز
And, I must ask you to come as well. You're suspected of abetting him.
،وسأطلب منكِ مرافقتنا أيضاً فأنتِ تحت شبهة تحريضه
You can't be serious...
...لا يمكن
That alright with you, Mr. Famous Detective?
أيناسبك ذلك أيّها المتحرّي الشهير؟
Of course! After all, he himself confessed to the murder...
بالطبع! فقد اعترف الفاعل ...بارتكابه الجريمة بنفسه
A mosquito this time of year...
...بعوضة في خارج موسمها
Not so fast, Detective Ezomatsu.
انتظر أيّها المحقق إيزوماتسو
Hiroshi-san did not murder Shuzo-san!
لم يقتل هيروشي-سان شوزو-سان
What kind of nonsense is this? He's already admitted to it...
ما هذا الهراء؟ اعترف بنفسه
Then, how do you explain the glass shards his arrow made?
كيف تفسّر شظايا الزجاج التي تناثرت بعدما أطلق هيروشي-سان السهم إذاً؟
Glass shards?
شظايا الزجاج؟
These? What about them?
هذه؟ وما فيها؟
Don't you find it odd?
ألا تجد الأمر غريباً؟
The arrow was shot from outside,
،أُطلق السهم من الخارج
and the resulting glass shards are all lined up.
وشظايا الزجاج المكسور متراصّة في خطّ
This is why I don't like amateurs, they tamper with crime scenes.
لهذا يُتعبنا الهواة، يعبثون بمسرح الجريمة
There was something lying here!
كان يوجد شيء هنا
Yes! The tempered glass had been placed there!
!صحيح، كان الزجاج المقوّى في ذاك المكان
Tempered glass?
الزجاج المقوّى؟
This?
هذا؟
And, just like that, Hiroshi-san fired the crossbow from outside!
وبذاك الوضع، أطلق هيروشي-سان بالقوس من الخارج
And then the glass shards fell to the ground...
...ثمّ تناثرت شظايا الزجاج على الأرض
What?!
!ماذا؟
Hold on! Wouldn't the arrow hit the tempered glass, too?!
تمهّل! ألا يُفترض أنّ السهم !أصاب الزجاج المقوّى أيضاً؟
Yes. The arrow hit the glass and struck the floor.
صحيح، أصاب السهم الزجاج المقوّى وعلق بالأرض
As tempered glass is clear, Hiroshi-san didn't notice from outside.
الزجاج المقوّى شفّاف، فلم يلحظ هيروشي-سان عند نظره من الخارج
Then where did the arrow in the victim's chest come from?!
من أين أتى السهم الذي !اخترق صدر الضحيّة إذاً؟
From inside the fireplace.
داخل موقد الحطب
Inside it is a part with soot removed.
به أجزاء أُزيح منها السخام
That's because a crossbow had been set up there.
ذلك لأنّ قوساً قد نُصّب هناك
But, how was it shot from inside here?!
لكن كيف أطلقه من الداخل؟
This.
بهذه
It was lying inside the fireplace.
كانت داخل الموقد
What's a wood chip got to do with anything?
بما ستفيد قطعة خشبية كهذه؟
First, you stick a wood chip with a string around it
أوّلاً، تحشر قطعة خشبية مربوطة بخيط
behind the trigger of the crossbow in the fireplace.
خلف زناد القوس المثبّت في الموقد
Next, you attach a strip of rubber around the trigger.
تربط شريطاً مطاطياً حول الزناد تالياً
The string tied to the wood chip is led up the chimney and outside.
الخيط المربوط بالقطعة الخشبية يمتدّ للمدخنة حتّى الخارج
The person with that string then looked through the skylight
نظر الشخص الذي كان مُمسكاً به من النافذة العلوية
and checked that Shuzo-san was sitting in his usual spot...
وتحقّق أنّ شوزو-سان كان جالساً في مكانه المعتاد
and then pulled the string just as Hiroshi-san fired his crossbow.
بعدها سحب الخيط مزامناً لإطلاق هيروشي-سان للقوس
That arrow struck Shuzo-san in the chest.
أصاب ذاك السهم شوزو-سان في صدره
The string left distinct marks inside the chimney.
ترك الخيط آثاراً واضحة داخل المدخنة
The arrow had fireplace soot on it, so analysis should confirm it.
،كان على السهم سخام من الموقد فسيؤكد التحليل الأمر
This was a premeditated murder?!
أي كانت جريمةً بسابق الإصرار والترصّد؟
Yes. A carefully premeditated one.
صحيح، بتمام الإصرار والترصّد
So, the killer took care of the glass and crossbow after the murder?!
أي كان القاتل من اهتمّ بأمر الزجاج المقوّى !والقوس بعد الجريمة؟
Hiroshi-san couldn't have done it, he had run off.
كان ذلك مستحيلاً على هيروشي-سان الذي فرّ
In other words, he's not the killer.
ما يعني أنّه ليس القاتل
The one who murdered Shuzo-san,
،من قتل شوزو-سان
and cleared away the glass, and crossbow in this locked room...
وتلاعب بالزجاج المقوّى والقوس ...في هذه الغرفة المقفلة
was you, Machida Tamotsu-san!
!كان أنت يا ماتشيدا تاموتسو-سان
But, three people were at the scene!
!لكن كان هناك ثلاثة أشخاص في مسرح الجريمة
They would've noticed the tempered glass had been moved!
!كانوا ليلاحظوا تغيّر مكان الزجاج المقوّى
No.
كلا
The first thing most people at a crime scene notice
أوّل ما تتوجّه له أنظار من يدخل مسرح جريمة قتل
is the victim.
هو الضحيّة
By quickly forcing them back into the hall,
،بمنعهم من الدخول سريعاً
they wouldn't be able to recall the condition of the room.
لن يستطيعوا تذكّر حال الغرفة
Moreover, you gave them orders to leave the scene.
إضافةً لذلك، أعطيت تعليمات للاثنين لإبعادهم عن المكان
Afterward, you took care of the tempered glass and crossbow.
بعدها، اهتممت بأمر الزجاج المقوّى والقوس
Your reason for murdering Shuzo-san
دافعك لقتل شوزو-سان
was likely because he refused to loan you money.
هو رفضه إقراضك غالباً
Damn! All any of you want is money!
!يا إلهي، كلّ ما تريدونه جميعاً هو المال
He didn't say that in regard to just them, but to you as well!
!لم يخصّهما بالذكر فحسب، بل شملك
So, you lured them here, into a trap.
لذا استدعيتَ هيروشي-سان وشقيقته ونصبتَ لهما فخّاً
After all, you wouldn't get any inheritance if you killed him yourself.
فلن تحصل على نصيب من الميراث إذا قتلتَه بنفسك
Sorry, Mori-san, but when my brother was murdered,
...للأسف يا موري-سان، عندما قُتل أخي
I was at the feeding ground drawing pictures, as you can see.
كنتُ في أرض الإطعام أرسم، كما ترى
The reason I suspected you was because of those drawings!
!اشتبهتُ بك بسبب تلك الرسمات تحديداً
The reason being that tanchous' tails aren't black!
فذيل طائر التانتشو ليس أسود
Their plumes are black, and their tails are white!
ريش جناحه هو الأسود، بينما ذيله أبيض
What's more, tanchous face the wind when they sleep.
إضافةً لذلك، تواجه التانتشو الرياح عند نومها
But, they're sleeping against the wind in your drawings.
لكنّها نائمة عكس الرياح في رسمتك
That's because you didn't draw them at the feeding ground,
،هذا لأنّك لم ترسمها في أرض الإطعام
you drew this stuffed one instead!
!بل رسمت المحشوّ هنا
Probably several days earlier, too!
وليس اليوم، بل قبل عدّة أيام غالباً
To make us think you drew them today,
،لتوهمنا أنّك رسمتها اليوم
you showed us an unused sketchbook.
أريتنا دفتر رسمٍ فارغ
Am I wrong?
أأنا مخطئ؟
It's true, I might've drawn their feathers incorrectly,
معك حقّ، لعلّي ارتكبتُ خطأً ،في رسم ريش التانتشو
but you haven't proven I didn't draw these there, either!
!لكنّك لم تثبت أنّي لم أرسمها هناك كذلك
Remember when you dropped your sketchbook at the hot spring?
أتتذكر إسقاطك لدفتر الرسم عند الينبوع الساخن؟
When you did, Conan caught it and gave it back to you.
أمسك به كونان وقتها وأعاده لك
Yes. Conan's fingerprints should be on your sketchbook.
أجل، يُفترض أن نجد بصمات كونان على دفتر الرسم ذاك
Assuming it's the same one, that is!
هذا إذا افترضنا أنّه الذي معك
I wiped it down when it got dirty later!
!مسحتُه لاحقاً لأنّه اتّسخ
Very well. The proof is the feather in your back pocket!
لا بأس، الدليل هي الريشة في جيب بنطالك الخلفيّ
A tanchou feather...
ر-ريشة تانتشو؟
No, it's not a tanchou feather.
كلا، ليست ريشة تانتشو
It's a feather of the turtledove that made a nest atop the chimney.
إنّها ريشة حمامة القُمرية التي بنت عشّاً أعلى المدخنة
It probably got there when you stuffed the string in your pocket.
علقت بجيبك عندما وضعت الخيط داخله غالباً
Ergo, there should be soot in your pocket, as well.
لذا يُفترض أنّنا سنجد سخاماً فيه كذلك
Unbelievable. Being suspected because of my drawings...
...عجباً، وقعتُ في الشبهة بسبب رسماتي
I guess I never did have any artistic talent...
يبدو أنّي لم أكن أتحلّى بموهبة في الرسم حقّاً
Just like my brother said, I lack observational skills.
كما قال أخي، أفتقر لمهارة الملاحظة
I've finally realized it.
استوعبتُ الأمر أخيراً
Entire Fortune Donated!! Migratory Bird Foundation Created.
!تبرّع بكامل ثروته! تأسيس مؤسسة الطيور المهاجرة
But, it's great that his children decided to follow in his footsteps
لكن من الرائع أنّ الابنين قرّرا اتّباع وصيّة ماتشيدا-سان
and take care of the tanchous...
والاعتناء بالتانتشو
But 300 million?
لكن ثلاثمئة مليون؟
I wanna be a tanchou and get taken care of...
أريد أن أصبح تانتشو ويُعتنى بي أيضاً
This guy never changes his ways...
لن يتعدّل هذا المُسن مهما حصل
Most of Mr. Dorakura's novels feature vampires,
معظم روايات السيّد دوراكورا تتضمّن ،مصّاصي الدماء كشخصيات رئيسية
so his nickname is "Mr. Dracula."
لذا يُلقّب بالسيّد دراكولا
All the windows were locked from the inside.
كانت كلّ النوافذ مُقفلة من الداخل
Which means the killer...
...ما يعني أنّ القاتل
...is an insider!
!من الدّاخل
On the next Conan: "The Dracula Manor Murder Case (Part 1)."
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Projector.
آلة عرض أفلام
When I say Dracula, what comes to mind?
...ما يتبادر لذهنك عند التفكير بدراكولا
Crosses.
!منتصف الليل
Garlic.
!لحم بشريّ
Korean barbecue.
!لحم مشويّ
That's not right.
ذلك لا ينطبق